Nicolás Cuesta Quintero

Financial Engineer

Contact

Medellín, Colombia (+57) 312 - 796 - 5598 nicolaicuesta@hotmail.com LinkedIn (click here) Personal Site (click here)

Key Skills

R / C++ Excel / VBA Microsoft Power BI Computational Finance Quantitative Finance

Activities and Interests

Financial Research
Capital Markets
Monopoly

Profile

Financial Engineer and candidate to a master's in computational and scientific modeling. Located in Medellín, Colombia, he considers himself as a methodic worker, Finance passionate and R enthusiast, always trying to tackle financial problems from a quantitative and computational perspective. His recent experience has let him improve his programming skills, learn about Business Intelligence and dive deep into real estate and alternative investments financial modeling.

Experience

March 2020—Present
Senior Power BI Developer • RealPage Inc. • Medellín, Colombia

May 2019—March 2020

Business Analyst • RealPage Inc. • Medellín, Colombia

He had the opportunity to help Business Intelligence teams in four crucial points: **knowledge management**, by allowing developers to better understand the business logic behind their datasets; **requirements management**, by translating clients' needs from a financial language to a technical one; **quality assurance**, creating business rules that final solutions must satisfy; and **data science**, by leveraging on R software to transform, organize and validate data, create new visualizations and models to understand data, and communicate business-oriented narratives.

August 2018—May 2019

Jr. Business Analyst • RealPage Inc. • Medellín, Colombia

He joined the valuations team as a Business Analyst to update quarterly valuations of properties all around the US. This experience let him understand better the common practices in Real Estate valuation, by applying the Discounted Cash Flow (DCF) methodology for offices and medical offices, as well as retail and mixed-use properties. He also had the opportunity to value storages and industrial properties and developed a tool for measuring changes in valuations due to capital markets.

December 2017—August 2019

SAP Engineer • ifb Group • Medellín, Colombia

This opportunity let him understand the way in which Financial Institutions are organized from the Back Office, and their relationship with new information technologies. He worked on Compliance for Foreign Investment Funds by creating regulatory reports for UCITS' and CPO's. Moreover, he was trained on SAP Bank Analyzer and SAP HANA. With the first one, he had the responsibility of verifying cash flow generation for consumer credits and corporate debt issues and keeping track of Amortized Cost calculations.

June 2017—December 2017

Intern • Isagén SA ESP • Medellín, Colombia

Financial risks intern who worked in three main projects: market risk models for short-term liquidity investments, implement an external CAMELS model to assess credit risk of foreign banks and developing a liquidity risk index.

Education

June 2021

MSc. Computational and Scientific Modeling • Universidad de Medellín

• Medellín, Colombia

March 2018

Financial Engineer • Universidad de Medellín • Medellín, Colombia